<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Blog | Jong creatief enzo</title>
 <link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog"/>
 <updated>2013-02-08T13:54:17+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://jcenzo.nl/blog</id>
 <author>
   <name>Mitchel van Eijgen</name>
   <email>Mitchel@jcenzo.nl</email>
 </author>

 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Henry's Statement</title>
 		<link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/henrys-statement"/>
 		<updated>1880-09-20T00:00:00+00:09</updated>
 		<id>http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/henrys-statement</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt; I was born in the year 18 &amp;mdash; to a large fortune, endowed besides with excellent parts, inclined by nature to industry, fond of the respect of the wise and good among my fellowmen, and thus, as might have been supposed, with every guarantee of an honourable and distinguished future. And indeed the worst of my faults was a certain impatient gaiety of disposition, such as has made the happiness of many, but such as I found it hard to reconcile with my imperious desire to carry my head high, and wear a more than commonly grave countenance before the public. Hence it came about that I concealed my pleasures; and that when I reached years of reflection, and began to look round me and take stock of my progress and position in the world, I stood already committed to a profound duplicity of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Many a man would have even blazoned such irregularities as I was guilty of; but from the high views that I had set before me, I regarded and hid them with an almost morbid sense of shame. It was thus rather the exacting nature of my aspirations than any particular degradation in my faults, that made me what I was, and, with even a deeper trench than in the majority of men, severed in me those provinces of good and ill which divide and compound man&amp;rsquo;s dual nature. In this case, I was driven to reflect deeply and inveterately on that hard law of life, which lies at the root of religion and is one of the most plentiful springs of distress. Though so profound a double-dealer, I was in no sense a hypocrite; both sides of me were in dead earnest; I was no more myself when I laid aside restraint and plunged in shame, than when I laboured, in the eye of day, at the futherance of knowledge or the relief of sorrow and suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>A Fortnight Later</title>
 		<link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/a-fortnight-later"/>
 		<updated>1880-09-15T00:00:00+00:09</updated>
 		<id>http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/a-fortnight-later</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt; A fortnight later, by excellent good fortune, the doctor gave one of his pleasant dinners to some five or six old cronies, all intelligent, reputable men and all judges of good wine; and Mr. Utterson so contrived that he remained behind after the others had departed. This was no new arrangement, but a thing that had befallen many scores of times. Where Utterson was liked, he was liked well. Hosts loved to detain the dry lawyer, when the light-hearted and loose-tongued had already their foot on the threshold; they liked to sit a while in his unobtrusive company, practising for solitude, sobering their minds in the man&amp;rsquo;s rich silence after the expense and strain of gaiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; To this rule, Dr. Jekyll was no exception; and as he now sat on the opposite side of the fire &amp;mdash; a large, well-made, smooth-faced man of fifty, with something of a stylish cast perhaps, but every mark of capacity and kindness &amp;mdash; you could see by his looks that he cherished for Mr. Utterson a sincere and warm affection.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Business Table</title>
 		<link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/business-table"/>
 		<updated>1880-09-07T00:00:00+00:09</updated>
 		<id>http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/business-table</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Next they turned to the business table. On the desk, among the neat array of papers, a large envelope was uppermost, and bore, in the doctor&amp;rsquo;s hand, the name of Mr. Utterson. The lawyer unsealed it, and several enclosures fell to the floor. The first was a will, drawn in the same eccentric terms as the one which he had returned six months before, to serve as a testament in case of death and as a deed of gift in case of disappearance; but in place of the name of Edward Hyde, the lawyer, with indescribable amazement read the name of Gabriel John Utterson. He looked at Poole, and then back at the paper, and last of all at the dead malefactor stretched upon the carpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My head goes round,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;He has been all these days in possession; he had no cause to like me; he must have raged to see himself displaced; and he has not destroyed this document.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He caught up the next paper; it was a brief note in the doctor&amp;rsquo;s hand and dated at the top. &amp;ldquo;O Poole!&amp;rdquo; the lawyer cried, &amp;ldquo;he was alive and here this day. He cannot have been disposed of in so short a space; he must be still alive, he must have fled! And then, why fled? and how? and in that case, can we venture to declare this suicide? O, we must be careful. I foresee that we may yet involve your master in some dire catastrophe.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Far Greater Proportion</title>
 		<link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/far-greater-proportion"/>
 		<updated>1880-09-04T00:00:00+00:09</updated>
 		<id>http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/far-greater-proportion</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The far greater proportion of the building was occupied by the theatre, which filled almost the whole ground storey and was lighted from above, and by the cabinet, which formed an upper story at one end and looked upon the court. A corridor joined the theatre to the door on the by-street; and with this the cabinet communicated separately by a second flight of stairs. There were besides a few dark closets and a spacious cellar. All these they now thoroughly examined. Each closet needed but a glance, for all were empty, and all, by the dust that fell from their doors, had stood long unopened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cellar, indeed, was filled with crazy lumber, mostly dating from the times of the surgeon who was Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s predecessor; but even as they opened the door they were advertised of the uselessness of further search, by the fall of a perfect mat of cobweb which had for years sealed up the entrance. No where was there any trace of Henry Jekyll dead or alive.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Wild, Cold</title>
 		<link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/wild-cold"/>
 		<updated>1880-09-02T00:00:00+00:09</updated>
 		<id>http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/wild-cold</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was a wild, cold, seasonable night of March, with a pale moon, lying on her back as though the wind had tilted her, and flying wrack of the most diaphanous and lawny texture. The wind made talking difficult, and flecked the blood into the face. It seemed to have swept the streets unusually bare of passengers, besides; for Mr. Utterson thought he had never seen that part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;London so deserted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He could have wished it otherwise; never in his life had he been conscious of so sharp a wish to see and touch his fellow-creatures; for struggle as he might, there was borne in upon his mind a crushing anticipation of calamity. The square, when they got there, was full of wind and dust, and the thin trees in the garden were lashing themselves along the railing. Poole, who had kept all the way a pace or two ahead, now pulled up in the middle of the pavement, and in spite of the biting weather, took off his hat and mopped his brow with a red pocket-handkerchief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for all the hurry of his coming, these were not the dews of exertion that he wiped away, but the moisture of some strangling anguish; for his face was white and his voice, when he spoke, harsh and broken.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Search for Mr. Hyde</title>
 		<link href="http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/search-for-mr-hyde"/>
 		<updated>1880-09-01T00:00:00+00:09</updated>
 		<id>http://jcenzo.nl/blog/artikelen/search-for-mr-hyde</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That evening Mr. Utterson came home to his bachelor house in sombre spirits and sat down to dinner without relish. It was his custom of a Sunday, when this meal was over, to sit close by the fire, a volume of some dry divinity on his reading desk, until the clock of the neighbouring church rang out the hour of twelve, when he would go soberly and gratefully to bed. On this night however, as soon as the cloth was taken away, he took up a candle and went into his business room. There he opened his safe, took from the most private part of it a document endorsed on the envelope as Dr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s Will and sat down with a clouded brow to study its contents. The will was holograph, for Mr. Utterson though he took charge of it now that it was made, had refused to lend the least assistance in the making of it; it provided not only that, in case of the decease of Henry Jekyll, M.D., D.C.L., L.L.D., F.R.S., etc., all his possessions were to pass into the hands of his &amp;ldquo;friend and benefactor Edward Hyde,&amp;rdquo; but that in case of Dr. Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;disappearance or unexplained absence for any period exceeding three calendar months,&amp;rdquo; the said Edward Hyde should step into the said Henry Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s shoes without further delay and free from any burthen or obligation beyond the payment of a few small sums to the members of the doctor&amp;rsquo;s household. This document had long been the lawyer&amp;rsquo;s eyesore. It offended him both as a lawyer and as a lover of the sane and customary sides of life, to whom the fanciful was the immodest.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 

</feed>